<idea-plugin>
    <id>io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager</id>
    <name>TODO Highlighter &amp; Comment Manager</name>
    <!-- version is patched in from build.gradle.kts (project version) -->
    <vendor url="https://github.com/J4sp3rTM">J4sp3r</vendor>
    <description><![CDATA[
        <p><b>TODO Highlighter &amp; Comment Manager</b> highlights and tracks <code>TODO</code>,
        <code>FIXME</code>, <code>HACK</code>, <code>NOTE</code>, and <code>XXX</code> comments
        across your source code — in <b>any language</b>, with editor highlighting, a dedicated tool
        window, structured metadata, and two-way editing.</p>

        <p>It understands a structured comment format:</p>
        <pre>// TODO [tag] (priority) description</pre>

        <h3>Features</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Tool window</b> with a tree view of every TODO in the project,
                grouped by file, tag, or priority.</li>
            <li><b>Locate &amp; preview</b> — show each item's file name or full path, hover for its
                path in a tooltip, and optionally preview items in a single reusable tab on click.</li>
            <li><b>Bidirectional editing</b> — change a TODO's description, tag, or priority
                from the panel and the source comment is rewritten in place (with full undo support).</li>
            <li><b>Editor highlighting</b> — keywords, tags, priorities, description text, and
                comment delimiters are colorized directly in the editor.</li>
            <li><b>Add &amp; complete</b> — insert new TODOs at the caret, or mark them done.</li>
            <li><b>Precise matching</b> — choose how keyword case is matched (any / upper-only /
                lower-only) and optionally require a keyword to be the first word on its line, so
                words like "note" mid-sentence aren't picked up. Optionally suppress the IDE's own
                built-in TODO highlighting so it doesn't double up with this plugin.</li>
            <li><b>Fully configurable</b> — customize keywords and all colors under
                <i>Settings &gt; Tools &gt; TODO Manager</i>.</li>
            <li><b>Auto-refresh</b> as you edit files.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>Works in all IntelliJ-based IDEs — IntelliJ IDEA, WebStorm, PyCharm, GoLand,
        PhpStorm, Rider, CLion, RubyMine, Android Studio, and more.</p>
    ]]></description>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <h3>1.7.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>File path in the tool window</b> — each item can show just the file name (default),
                the path from the project root, or the full absolute path. Configure it under
                <i>Settings &gt; Tools &gt; TODO Manager</i>.</li>
            <li><b>Hover tooltip</b> — hovering an item reveals its path (project-relative by default,
                or absolute / file name), handy for reading long paths at a glance. It can be turned
                off entirely.</li>
            <li><b>Preview on single click</b> — optionally open items in the editor's reusable preview
                tab with a single click, so clicking through TODOs doesn't pile up tabs. Editing the
                file or double-clicking promotes it to a normal tab. (Turning this on enables the IDE's
                "Open files in preview tab" option; it is restored when turned off.)</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.6.1</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Fix</b> — the getting-started tour is now offered through a first-run notification
                instead of opening automatically as a dialog, so it never interrupts startup (and no
                longer blocks automated IDE/plugin-install checks). Click <i>Start tour</i> in the
                notification, or open it any time from <i>Help &gt; TODO Manager: Getting Started</i>.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.6.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Getting-started tour</b> — a short, visual onboarding shown on first run: how markers
                are highlighted, the <code>KEYWORD [tag] (priority) description</code> format, and where
                the tool window lives. It can drop you straight into creating your first TODO.</li>
            <li>Re-open the tour any time from <i>Help &gt; TODO Manager: Getting Started</i>.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.5.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Scans the whole project by default</b> — TODOs in folders with any name (and their
                sub-folders) are now picked up, instead of only auto-detected source directories.
                Excluded and IDE-ignored folders are still skipped, and source-only scanning can be
                re-enabled in settings.</li>
            <li><b>Empty-state guidance</b> — when there is nothing to show, the tool window now says so;
                if scanning is limited to source directories but none exist, it offers a link straight
                into the settings to add one.</li>
            <li><b>Fix</b> — no longer throws a <i>Read access is allowed from inside read-action only</i>
                error when marking a TODO as done or deleting it.</li>
            <li><b>Fix</b> — the settings page now scrolls with the mouse wheel, not only the scrollbar.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.4.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Group by keyword</b> — a new <i>Keyword</i> option in the <i>Group by</i> menu.</li>
            <li><b>Keyword filter</b> — a toolbar dropdown to show only items with a chosen keyword,
                or <i>All</i> to show every keyword.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.3.1</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Collapse by default</b> — a <i>Collapse</i> toolbar toggle to start groups collapsed
                instead of fully expanded.</li>
            <li><b>Expand/collapse state preserved on refresh</b> — refreshing keeps each group the way
                you left it; newly appearing groups follow the collapse-by-default setting.</li>
            <li><b>Reverse sort</b> — a <i>Reverse</i> toolbar toggle that flips the group order and the
                items within each group.</li>
            <li><b>Live updates</b> — the tool window now refreshes as TODOs are added, changed, or
                removed in the editor, without waiting for the file to be saved.</li>
            <li><b>Fix</b> — no longer logs a <i>write-unsafe context</i> error while typing; the live
                re-scan now runs only once the edited document's PSI is committed.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.2.1</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Fix</b> — no longer throws an <code>IndexOutOfBoundsException</code> when scanning a
                file whose content has just changed (the comment offsets could briefly outrun the
                reloaded document). Affected files now re-scan once the editor catches up.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.2.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Keyword case matching</b> — choose <i>Any case</i>, <i>Upper-case only</i>, or
                <i>Lower-case only</i> so a lower-case <code>note</code> in prose isn't mistaken for
                the <code>NOTE</code> keyword.</li>
            <li><b>First-word matching</b> — optionally only recognize a keyword when it's the first
                word on its line, so keywords appearing mid-sentence are ignored.</li>
            <li><b>Suppress IDE TODO highlighting</b> — optionally clear the IDE's own built-in
                TODO highlighting so it doesn't double up with this plugin (restored when turned off).</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.1.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Create <b>general (code-free) TODOs</b> from the panel — check "General TODO" in the
                New TODO dialog to track items that aren't attached to any comment.</li>
            <li><b>Mark as Done</b> now stamps the completion with your git user name and the date,
                e.g. <code>DONE fix login (done by J4sp3r on 2026-06-29)</code>.</li>
            <li><b>Completed items stay visible</b> — DONE comments and done general todos are shown
                struck through with a "done by … on …" label. Toggle them with <b>Show done</b> in
                the toolbar.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.0.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Initial release</li>
            <li>Tool window with tree view of all TODO/FIXME/HACK/NOTE comments</li>
            <li>Structured comment format: // TODO [tag] (priority) description</li>
            <li>Group by file, tag, or priority</li>
            <li>Bidirectional editing: change priority/tag/description in panel → updates source</li>
            <li>Add new TODOs from the panel</li>
            <li>Mark TODOs as done</li>
            <li>Configurable keywords and patterns</li>
            <li>Auto-refresh on file changes</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <!-- Tool window in the bottom panel -->
        <toolWindow
            id="TODO Manager"
            anchor="bottom"
            factoryClass="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.TodoToolWindowFactory"
            icon="/icons/todo.svg"/>

        <!-- Settings page under Settings > Tools -->
        <applicationConfigurable
            parentId="tools"
            instance="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.TodoManagerConfigurable"
            id="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.settings"
            displayName="TODO Manager"/>

        <!-- Persistent state for settings -->
        <applicationService
            serviceImplementation="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.TodoManagerSettings"/>

        <!-- Project-level scanner service -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.TodoScannerService"/>

        <!-- Persistent store for general (code-free) todos -->
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.GeneralTodoStore"/>

        <!-- Paints TODO highlighting into editor markup models. Done this way (rather than via an
             annotator) so it works for every language even in files where the IDE disables
             code-insight highlighting, e.g. loose Java/Kotlin files outside a source root. -->
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.TodoHighlightingActivity"/>

        <!-- Invites the user into the onboarding tour once per installation (non-modal). -->
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.OnboardingActivity"/>

        <!-- Notification group for the first-run onboarding invitation. -->
        <notificationGroup
            id="TODO Manager Onboarding"
            displayType="STICKY_BALLOON"/>

        <!-- Renames the tab opened by the tool window's single-click preview to "Preview: <file>". -->
        <editorTabTitleProvider
            implementation="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.TodoPreviewTabTitleProvider"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <!-- Lets users re-open the onboarding tour any time. -->
        <action
            id="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.ShowOnboarding"
            class="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.ShowOnboardingAction"
            text="TODO Manager: Getting Started"
            description="Show the TODO Manager onboarding tour">
            <add-to-group group-id="HelpMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
    </actions>

    <projectListeners>
        <listener
            class="io.github.j4sp3rtm.todomanager.TodoFileListener"
            topic="com.intellij.openapi.vfs.newvfs.BulkFileListener"/>
    </projectListeners>
</idea-plugin>
